jobtarget.com 2014-12-03

# Privacy Policy & Statement - Privacy, Data & Analytics | JobTarget

JobTarget maintains a great respect for the privacy and security of our users. We recognize that the reason we can remain in business is because of you. Therefore we will do nothing to jeopardize your trust and loyalty.

JobTarget hosts and manages over 1,000 career Websites on behalf of our Partners. If you visit a career site that is powered by JobTarget, you may also see our Partner’s logos, trademarks, and proprietary trade documentation on that Website. We strongly recommend that you also review our Partner’s Privacy Policy before using the Website. If you disagree with the way we collect, process and display personal and non-personal information on our Websites, do not use them.

Although we make every effort to keep information confidential in accordance with the functionality of our Websites, JobTarget cannot and does not guarantee the security, confidentiality, or privacy of any information or communication that you submit to us.

**TRUSTe**  
JobTarget has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html "TRUSTe's program requirements") including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information.  The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software.  The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site, [www.jobtarget.com](http://www.jobtarget.com/) and does not cover information that may be collected through behind the log in on our website. 

TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy Trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [privacy@jobtarget.com](mailto:privacy@jobtarget.com).  If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact TRUSTe [here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint).

**U.S.—E.U. Safe Harbor**  
JobTarget complies with the U.S. – E.U.  Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of personal information from the from European Union member countries. JobTarget has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement.  To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view JobTarget’s certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>.

## Information Collected by JobTarget

**Jobtarget.com**  
Visitors to our Website remain anonymous unless they elect to register an account on our Website, or request information from JobTarget. We require certain personal information to register accounts as well as respond to your inquiries about our Website and service. This information includes name, email address, phone number, and company physical address. We also collect sensitive information such as credit card number and cvc code to fulfill payment for services purchased on the Website. We also use your personal information to send users surveys. We do not share any of this personal information with third parties for their promotional purposes.

We reserve the right to disclose information to our services providers. We employ the services of a third party payment processor to fulfill payment on transactions. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us. We also reserve the right to share information with law enforcement and government agencies where a formal request has been made such as in a civil suit, court order, subpoena or judicial proceeding, or where necessary in protecting our intellectual property, the safety of our staff, users or the general public. We post testimonials from our users’ on the Website. These testimonials include user names. We obtain consent to include this information within testimonials prior to posting on the Website. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [support@jobtarget.com](mailto:support@jobtarget.com). 

We send notification emails about the Website and the service from time to time as necessary. Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to deactivate your account.

We also send newsletters to our users with news of new service offerings and promotions. Should you change your mind about receiving these newsletters, you can unsubscribe by following the directions present in each email we send out.

**EmployAnalytics**  
JobTarget’s EmployAnalytics ("EA") service is designed to provide analytical data and statistics to employers that post recruitment advertisements through JobTarget’s distribution channels. JobTarget acts as an agent of the employer by collecting user personal and non-personal information during the job application process.

The EA service uses proxy servers to collect, retain and pass along your information to employers. Our Websites collect information from visitors, including job seekers, employers, recruiters and advertising agencies ("users"). JobTarget may collect personal information about you when you choose to apply to a job through EA. Some examples of personal information that we collect include: your name, address, email address, telephone number, credit card number, contact information, IP address, billing information, profession, work experience, and information about third parties, such as contacts or references that you provide to us.

This information may be analyzed and used to generate aggregate statistics and to determine use patterns and effective job placement to better serve you in the future. We may also collect behavioral information regarding how you use our sites and the areas of our site that you visit to better serve you in the future.

All personal information will be processed and stored by JobTarget in the United States. United States laws regarding processing of personal information may be less stringent than the laws in your jurisdiction.

## How Information is Used by JobTarget

**Jobtarget.com**  
JobTarget collects personal and non-personal information to perform the service of matching job seekers up with potential employers. Our goal is to provide a beneficial and positive experience for all parties using our services. By utilizing our services, you have agreed to allow us to use your information, subject to local law, in the following manner: To create a job seeker profile for you based on information you have provided to us; To provide information about you to employers and recruiters at your request; To create an employer profile based on the information you have provided us; To provide information about you and your recruitment advertisements to job seekers at your request; If an employer uses JobTarget’s technology to post an advertisement to a third party job board, that employer’s contact information may be shared with the operator of that third party; To contact you regarding changes to your profile, service updates, products and services you may be interested in, surveys, sweepstakes, and various other communications regarding our products and services. We do not sell your personal information to anyone for any reason without your consent. You may elect to opt out of any communications sent to you at any time. Job seekers may elect to have their profile and contact information kept private at any time by logging in and changing the setting of their profile. You may request that we change the settings of your profile for you by emailing us at [support@jobtarget.com](mailto:support@jobtarget.com).

If you use our service to build or post a resume in our database, you will be providing us with personal information that will be used in accordance with our Privacy Policy.

**EmployAnalytics**  
JobTarget collects personal and non-personal information as part of submitting a job-seeker application to an Employer for their online job application process. This information is obtained from the user via proxy server and submitted to the employer at the user’s request and direction. JobTarget uses this data to conduct various measures of job posting effectiveness, accuracy, posting locations, business intelligence regarding the placement of job advertisements, the content of job advertisements, and the conversion of users from viewing a job advertisement to submitting a completed job advertisement for an open position. Our goal is to provide a beneficial and positive experience for all parties using our services by developing deep insight into the process of matching jobseekers with employers through the right job advertisements. By utilizing our services, you have agreed to allow us to use your information, subject to local law, in the following manner: To create a job seeker profile for you based on information you have provided to us; To provide information about you to employers and recruiters at your request; To provide information about you to employers specifically as a part of the interactive job application process; To provide information about you and your application habits to the employers whose job postings you view, follow, or submit jobs through; To create an employer profile based on the information you have provided us; To provide information about you and your recruitment advertisements to job seekers at your request.

JobTarget does not disclose personal information to third parties without your consent. If you select a product or service on our site that is offered by one of our affiliates, you may be redirected to that affiliate’s website, and some of your personal information may be provided to that affiliate in order to assist them with the transaction. Please be aware that our Affiliates may use your information consistent with their own Privacy Policy, which may be inconsistent with our Privacy Policy.

JobTarget may be required to disclose your personal information to law enforcement officials to cooperate with the law. This disclosure would be to protect the interests of JobTarget and its users.

## Third Party Sites

We provide links on our Website to third party sites. These links are provided to visitors and users as a courtesy. We have no authority over, or take responsibility for the information practices of these third party sites and encourage you to review their privacy and information practices prior to disclosing your personal information.

## Security

JobTarget will take measures to protect your information from unauthorized or inappropriate use by third parties. JobTarget has no control over these third parties, so we cannot be responsible for their use of the information. JobTarget cannot guarantee that your information will always remain private. Our users assume all responsibility and risk for the use of our websites. JobTarget employs industry accepted standards in protecting your personal information while on our Website. JobTarget uses 128 bit SSL encryption to manage our payment processing. JobTarget is compliant with the PCI scan validation requirement. All web site data is hosted and stored in a database of servers in the United States.

## Cookies, Web Beacons and Flash LSOs

JobTarget uses cookies for your convenience and security. Cookies are text files stored on your computer. The cookies remember information that you’ve already typed in our web site fields, so you don’t have to enter them again. They are used to make your experience on web sites more personal and less cumbersome. We do link information stored in cookies to personally identifiable information you submit while on our site. You should have the ability to change whether or not cookies are used through your web browser. Please refer to your web browser’s help function for assistance on how to change your preferences. We may also apply the use of web beacons in our email communications and Website from time to time. A web beacon is a one pixel by one pixel image embedded within a web page for page view tracking purposes. Web beacons are not tied to personal information on the Website. Like most other Websites, we also make use of log files which include users IP address, referring URL and pages viewed within a session.

We use local shared objects, also known as Flash cookies, to store your preferences such as volume control or high game score, or display content based upon what you view on our site to personalize your visit.  Third Parties, with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity, use Flash cookies to collect and store information.

Flash cookies are different from browser cookies because of the amount of, type of, and how data is stored.  Cookie management tools provided by your browser will not remove Flash cookies.  To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies click here: <http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html#117118>

If you use our service to build or post a resume in our database, you will be providing us with personal information that will be used in accordance with our Privacy Policy.

**Proxy Server**  
JobTarget uses proxy servers to collect information from job seekers during the EA application process. When a job seeker clicks the ÒApply HereÓ link in a job description, they are redirected to the employer’s application page, via JobTarget’s proxy server. The proxy server collects personal and non-personal information on behalf of the employer. Personal information may include profession, work history, contacts and references. All information gathered is used to improve the job seeker application process. A link to JobTarget’s Privacy Policy is displayed on the bottom of the page during the proxy server application process.

**Third Party Cookies**  
We have third party advertisers on the site who may employ the use of cookies and web beacons on the Website in tracking the effectiveness of their advertisements. We have no access to these third party cookies. We may also employ the services of a third party agent in tracking aggregated statistical data about our Website. This non personal information is used for statistical purposes and these third parties may also employ the use of cookies and web beacons in providing this service to us.

## Behavioral Targeting / Re-Targeting

We partner with a third party ad network to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites.  Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on this and other Web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests.  If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences.truste.com/).  Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising.  You will continue to receive generic ads.

## Changes to your Account

You may update, delete or modify any of the personal information submitted to our Website by sending an email to us at [support@jobtarget.com](mailto:support@jobtarget.com).

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services.  We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

## Subject to Change

The terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy are subject to change at any time by updating this page. Periodically, you should return and review this privacy statement. Any use of the site following the posting of any new or modified privacy agreement constitutes your acceptance of the modified agreement. Should we make any material changes to the manner in which we use your collected information, we shall notify you by means of a prominent notice on the Website, or by email.

## Comments and questions may be sent to:

JobTarget  
225 State St.   
Suite 300   
New London, CT 06320   

If you encounter a user that is in violation of the terms of this Privacy Policy, or if you believe a user is inappropriately using our services, please email us immediately at [privacy@jobtarget.com](mailto:privacy@jobtarget.com). We shall respond to all inquiries within 30 days of receipt.

Last Updated: April 30, 2013
